# Shrikanth Narayanaswamy Chandrasekaran

website: https://snaraya7.github.io/ e-mail: snaraya7@ncsu.edu or nc.shrikanth@gmail.com

**Ph.D.** candidate in Computer Science at NC State University, USA (Advised by Prof. Tim Menzies) with 10 years of industry experience. My research interest includes Software Engineering and Machine Learning (*Graduating* - December 2021).

RESEARCH (Research Assistant, North Carolina State University) 2017 to present

Interest: Software Engineering and Machine Learning | Focus area: Software Quality Assurance | **Lab:** RAISE(<a href="http://ai4se.net/">http://ai4se.net/</a>) Advisor: Dr. Tim Menzies (<a href="http://menzies.us/">http://menzies.us/</a>) Our recent empirical study confirms that "96% of the time, we do not want and we do not need data-hungry methods" (refer to publication [1] below).

**OTHER RESEARCH AREAS**: Code Retrieval, Crowdsourcing, Test case prioritization, and Software Maintenance.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 - Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science at North Carolina State University (*Graduating* - December 2021)

2004 – 2008: 4 year full-time **Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication**, Saveetha Engineering College, affiliated to Anna University – Chennai

#### **SKILLS**

- \* Programming: Java (SCJP and SCWCD certified) & Python. Fundamentals: Data Structures, Algorithms & Compilers
- ❖ Statistics: Hypotheses testing, effect size, analysis of distributions, etc
- \* Machine Learning: Predictive/Estimate modeling, Weka data mining, scikit, Deep learning (Tensorflow, CNN & RNN) Carrot2, ELK, and OPEN NLP. Visualization: Plotly, MATLAB, R, etc.
- \* Front-End: Java Swing, Eclipse Plugin development, and HTML-CSS. Database: RDBMS (MySQL & MariaDB).
- ❖ Distributed computing: Python multiprocessing on High-Performance computing
- etc.,

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. N. C. Shrikanth, Suvodeep Majumder, and Tim Menzies. Early Life Cycle Software Defect Prediction. Why? How? (To appear in ICSE '21).
- **2. N. C. Shrikanth**, William Nichols, Fahmid Morshed Fahid, and Tim Menzies. Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Engineering. (To appear in EMSE '21 Journal).
- 3. N. C. Shrikanth, and Tim Menzies. 2020. Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Defect Prediction. (ICSE '20 SEIP) (Best Paper Nominee).
- **4.** Anurag Dwarakanath, **N. C. Shrikanth**, Kumar Abhinav, and Alex Kass. 2016. Trustworthiness in enterprise crowdsourcing: a taxonomy & evidence from data. (**ICSE** '16 SEIP).
- 5. Anurag Dwarakanath, Upendra Chintala, **Shrikanth N. C.**, Gurdeep Virdi, Alex Kass, Anitha Chandran, Shubhashis Sengupta, and Sanjoy Paul. 2015. CrowdBuild: a methodology for enterprise software development using crowdsourcing (CSI-SE ICSE '15).

### **GRANTED PATENTS**

- 1. Method and system for visual requirements and component reuse driven rapid application composition
- 2. Incident Prediction and Prevention
- 3. Generating a Test Script Execution Order

# Shrikanth Narayanaswamy Chandrasekaran

website: <a href="https://snaraya7.github.io/">https://snaraya7.github.io/</a> e-mail: <a href="mailto:snaraya7@ncsu.edu">snaraya7@ncsu.edu</a> or <a href="mailto:nc.shrikanth@gmail.com">nc.shrikanth@gmail.com</a>

### INDUSTRY EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Summer 2021 Microsoft, USA

#### Role: Research Intern

Developer Satisfaction (productivity): Perform large-scale data analysis on software engineers' feedback about their day-to-day work and hundreds of software repositories to offer actionable recommendations (machine learning models) to improve developer satisfaction across a large unit within Microsoft.

## Summer 2020 Fujitsu Laboratories of America, USA

## Role: Research Intern

Low code platform: Improved deep learning-based 'Code Retrieval' models (using CodeBERT & CodeSearchNet deep learning models) that catalyze developer productivity.

## 2014 – 2017 Accenture Labs, India

## Role: Technology R&D Specialist

- Crowdsourcing: Performed large scale data analysis to find obstacles for enterprises to crowdsource software development
- Log Analysis: Analyzed voluminous incident tickets and their associated log files of a supermarket chain to prescribe solutions to minimize incident resolution time.
- Recognized for outstanding contributions

## 2011 – 2014 ABB India Limited, Bangalore India

Role: Software Engineer | Software Development, LV Systems R&D

- Managed the software life-cycle of a standalone Low voltage switchgear configuration and reporting product.
- Star Employee for a quarter

## 2008 – 2011 Infosys Limited, Chennai India

# **Role: Senior Systems Engineer**

- Developed rich user interface rich integration tools that ease software developers to orchestrate banking services.
- Finacle on the spot award
- Certifications: Sun Certified Java Programmer and Sun Certified Web Component Developer

### **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

- 1. CSC 440 Database Management Systems Instructor: Dr. Rada Chirkova
- 2. CSC 495 Software Testing Instructor: Dr. Kathryn T. Stolee
- 3. CSC 510 Software Engineering Instructors: Dr. Jamie Jennings, Dr. Nicholas A. Kraft, and Dr. Emerson Murphy-Hill

## REVIEWER

- ★ Empirical Software Engineering Journal
- ★ Information and Software Technology Journal

#### **TALKS**

- ❖ ICSE'21 Early Life Cycle Software Defect Prediction. Why? How? <a href="https://youtu.be/oHCUJnWygDk">https://youtu.be/oHCUJnWygDk</a>
- ❖ ICSE'20 Assessing Practitioner Beliefs about Software Defect Prediction https://youtu.be/UokXMoP-v7Q?t=2094
- ❖ ICSE'20 What Disconnects Practitioner Belief and Empirical Evidence <a href="https://youtu.be/UbuG6UwVzuU">https://youtu.be/UbuG6UwVzuU</a>